<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>JHylaFAX</title>
    <author>Steffen Pingel</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="JHylaFAX">
      <p>A Java client licensed under the GPL for the <a
		  href="http://www.hylafax.org" target="_blank">HylaFAX</a>
		  fax server. JHylaFAX is purely written in Java and runs on
		  any Java 6.0 enabled platform. It has a small footprint,
		  starts up fast and features a sleek user interface.</p>

	  <p><a href="screenshots.html"><img align="right"
	  src="images/main-window-1.3.1-small.png"
	  border="0"></img></a></p>

	  <p><b>Features</b></p>
	  
	  <ul>
		<li>Faxing of documents in PostScript format</li>
		<li>Polling of faxes</li>
		<li>Automatic generation and preview of cover page</li>
		<li>Editing of fax job parameters</li>
		<li>Viewing and deleting of received faxes and stored
		documents</li>
		<li>Support for HylaFAX admin mode</li>
		<li>Monitoring of files with automatic popup of send dialog</li>
		<li>Address book that supports vCard import and export as well
		as importing SuSEFax address books</li>
		<li>Language support: English, German, Spanish, Italian,
		Portuguese, French, Turkish, Polish, Catalan, Czech and Dutch</li>
	  </ul>

	  <p><b>Requirements</b></p>
      <ul>
		<li><a href="http://java.sun.com/javase/6/"
		target="_blank">Java 6.0</a> (JRE)</li>
	  </ul>

	  <p><b>Optional</b></p>
	  <ul>
		<li>An image program to view TIFF G3 files (like kfax) for
		received faxes</li>
		<li>A program to view PostScript files (like ghostview) for
		preview and stored documents</li>
		<li>A running HylaFAX server (otherwise JHylaFAX is pretty useless)</li>
	  </ul>

	  <p>JHylaFAX can be integrated with the native printing
	  system of Windows or Unix (CUPS). See <a href="manual.html">the
	  manual</a> for details.</p>

	  <subsection name="About the Project">
		<p>The first release of JHylaFAX was developed in 1999 based
		  on <a
		  href="http://www.novell.com/products/linuxpackages/professional/susefax.html">SuSEFax</a>
		  by Carsten Hoeger. The goal was to provide a more intuitive
		  user interface based on the - at that time - brand new Swing
		  library. Unfotunatelly the development was stopped before
		  the code reached a stable state. The 0.3.5 release of
		  JHylaFAX looks nice, but the code is unreadable, badly
		  synchronized, features quite a few race conditions and ugly
		  handling of modal dialogs can lead to dead locks every once
		  in a while.</p>

		<p>The current release is a complete rewrite that serves as a
		  testbed for the XNap Commons library and learning experience
		  for the cool new Java 5.0 language enhancements. It makes
		  use of the gnu.hylafax library for the server communication
		  and uses JGoodies Forms for the GUI layout. The only part
		  that is still based on SuSEFax code handles the cover page
		  generation. <a href="dependencies.html">This page</a>
		  contains a complete list of the dependencies.</p>
	  </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
